Carbon border adjustment mechanism is a
new tax which is going to be now
implemented here in Europe and it
targets in particular
Chinese and Indian exports to the EU
particularly aluminum, cement,
fertilizers and steel. The Europeans
believe that these products in
particular are produced in an
environment that contributes to
greenhouse gas emissions and therefore
pollutes the air. They want to target
these products by a new carbon price to
put more pressure on the Chinese and the
Indians to invest more in clean
technology and also in emissions
tracking systems. That's number one.
Number two, they want to prevent
European companies from relocating to uh
China and India where the costs are
lower compared to the EU and they want
to provide a fair competition for
European companies and the Europeans are
sending here a political message at the
same time which is basically they're
using their leverage to tell the other
countries such as India, China, Russia,
Brazil and South Africa that it's about
time to contribute to the push to create
a better world with renewable energy,
less pollution, or you will risk a share
in the European market. But ultimately
this is a move that it may lead to an
increase in some of the products for the
European themselves particularly when it
comes to garden tools, kitchen stoves,
refri refrigerators and also car
components. The Chinese and the Indians
were very upset with this new tax. They
hit back and said this is a unilateral
approach by the Europeans. But from a
European perspective, there is a
consensus that everyone who wants to do
business with the Europeans has to meet
the EU environmental standards. Hashb
Alazer, Brussels.
Don't miss out. Get [music] the full
picture. Subscribe to Alazer for
reliable news, expert insight. Like,
share. Stay ahead.